# **Dede Permana**

### FRONT END DEVELOPER

Email: dpermana350@gmail.com

Phone: 089667862647

<u>LinkedIn:</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/dede-permana/ <u>Personal Website</u>: https://dedepermana.vercel.app/

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Software Engineer with almost 2 years of experience. I specialize in the frontend and I have up-to-date knowledge of modern technologies, including React, Next Js and TypeScript. Implemented complex reusable components and mini-frameworks that were used across an entire organization. Composed and reviewed design docs. Detected architecture problems, proposed solutions, and coordinated multiple teams to fix the issues.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Universitas Amikom Yogykarta**

Bachelor of Informatics | 2022

GPA: 3.83

#### SMK Negeri 2 Depok Sleman

Computer Network Engineering | 2017

### **SKILLS**

• HTML & CSS (Expert)

Javascript (Intermediate)
Tailwind (Intermediate)
React JS (Intermediate)

• Next JS (Intermediate)

• TypeScript (Basic)

Redux (Intermediate)GIT (Intermediate)

### **CERTIFICATE**

### Sertifikat Kampus Merdeka

https://bit.ly/Sertifikat-Kampus-Merdeka-Hacktiv8

### Dicoding Fundamental Front-End Web Development

https://www.dicoding.com/certificates/GRX5K Q3JRZ0M

### Dicoding Front-End Web Untuk Pemula

https://www.dicoding.com/certificates/JMZVM 731JZN9

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Front End Engineer**

PT Kode Inovasi Teknologi (CODR) | Jul 2022 -Now

#### Front End Developer Intern

Circlegeo | Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

- Develop functional and appealing web applications based on usability
- Provide web apps maintenance and enhancements
- Write functional requirement documents and specifications
- Convert mockups and prototypes on tight timelines
- Process and visualize data from API
- Develop Plugins based on 2000++ applications owned by community members

## Front End React Development (Kampus Merdeka)

Hacktiv8 | Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- Understand Basic Programmer Mindset & Technical Fundamentals to become a website programmer.
- Understand and know the basic skillset that a front-end developer must have.
- Understand and implement the React library for the front-end development of web applications and mobile apps.
- Debug and optimize the performance of the website & application created.

### **Assistant Lecturer**

Universitas Amikom Yogyakarta | Sep 2019 - Jul 2021

- · Help lecturers in making the subject matter
- Help students with understanding the materials and troubleshooting if there are errors
- Assist in the recording of student grades
- Some of the subjects are Programming Algorithms (C++), Programming (C#), Data Structures (C++), Advanced Programming (C#), and Web Programming (HTML, CSS, Javascript)

#### **Graphic Designer Intern**

Gamatechno | Jan 2017 - Jun 2017